<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Blog de DD</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Blog de DD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Escher&#39;s Sphere</title>
      <link>/post/2022/12/14/eschers-sphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022/12/14/eschers-sphere/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Figure 1: Escher’s Sphere Escher created three dimensional spaces that never existed with mathematical precision. He also was very good at conveying a sense of depth on a flat surface. All without the aid of a computer.
About this sphere (made in 1958) he wrote: “Curved ribbons or strips are suited to suggest a three dimensionality… A system of four theoretically never ending ribbons running over the surface of the sphere linking at the poles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphing between posiitive and Negative</title>
      <link>/post/2022/12/14/morphplusneg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022/12/14/morphplusneg/</guid>
      <description>This notebook shows how to use some of the tools in the package aPhotoDeDD.^[current location is (https://github.com/dashdotdotdashdotdot/aPhotoDeDD)] As this is an R Notebook, you can read the .html version on a browser or you can bring up the .Rmd version in Rstudio and run it line by line and make changes as desired. The animation that this program produces is posted on the instagram site of @dashdotdotdashdot: instagram. The idea is to run it once at a low resolution first with a small number of frames to see that it works before committing to creating a relatively large .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog de DD</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a blog to organize and keep track of my work in one place. I started it on December 13, 2022. Below are some external links to some of my work.
Instagram: @dashdotdotdashdotdot
My piece in the Bridges 2021 Mathematical Art Gallery: Escher&amp;rsquo;s Sphere Bridges 2021 Conference
My paper in the Bridges 2022 Mathematical Art Conference (Bridges Aalto 2022): Spiral Based Point Cloud Representations of Sculptures Bridges Aalto 2022 Conference</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
