<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R art on Blog de DD</title>
    <link>/categories/r-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R art on Blog de DD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/r-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Algorithimic Figure Ground Reversal</title>
      <link>/post/2022/12/14/algogroundreversal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022/12/14/algogroundreversal/</guid>
      <description>Artists have long been fascinated with the concepts of figure and ground reversals. In this note, we show how to execute such techniques with mathematical operations on photographs. We will start with two images. The image on the left is one of a chess board. It is a photograph that I have taken. The image on the right is &amp;ldquo;Silhouet van Madame Eugène de Block-Looz,&amp;rdquo; which is a &amp;ldquo;snipping&amp;rdquo; done by Charles Auguste Fraikin in 1852 and is available on website of the Rijks Museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphing between posiitive and Negative</title>
      <link>/post/2022/12/14/morphplusneg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022/12/14/morphplusneg/</guid>
      <description>This notebook shows how to use some of the tools in the package aPhotoDeDD.^[current location is (https://github.com/dashdotdotdashdotdot/aPhotoDeDD)] As this is an R Notebook, you can read the .html version on a browser or you can bring up the .Rmd version in Rstudio and run it line by line and make changes as desired. The animation that this program produces is posted on the instagram site of @dashdotdotdashdot: instagram. The idea is to run it once at a low resolution first with a small number of frames to see that it works before committing to creating a relatively large .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping Ribbons Around Donuts</title>
      <link>/post/2022/12/14/wrappingribons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022/12/14/wrappingribons/</guid>
      <description>Introduction $${\sqrt {n}}\left(\left({\frac {1}{n}}\sum _{i=1}^{n}X_{i}\right)-\mu \right)\ {\xrightarrow {d}}\ N\left(0,\sigma ^{2}\right)$$
Beautiful imagery can be created by &amp;ldquo;wrapping&amp;rdquo; curves around a &amp;ldquo;donut&amp;rdquo; or a &amp;ldquo;torus&amp;rdquo;. In this note, we describe how the formulas that accomplish this work. It is useful to imagine a clock with one hand fixed to the edge of a turntable. The clock is positioned such that the line between the center of the turntable and the center of the clock contains &amp;ldquo;9 o&amp;rsquo;clock&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;plane containing the clock face&amp;rdquo; is perpendicular to the plane of the turntable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
